# **Quang Tran**

UI Engineer at Apple Inc.

#### **Profile**

I have 4-year experience in building web applications using modern web framework (ReactJS ecosystem). I am looking for a full-time position in a collaborative environment where I can make impacts and develop products that customers love.

#### **Details**

3321 Latham Dr Garland, TX 75044 quangta93@gmail.com 469-231-8107

## **Employment History**

#### **UI Engineer at Apple Inc**

May 2018 - Present

- Building internal UI applications using ReactJS ecosystem.
- As the only UI engineer on my team, I released first production version within 5 months since the hire date.
- The application is running on hundreds of machines for more than 6 months without major crashes.

#### Lead Software Engineer at Flywheel B.I.

September 2015 - April 2018

- Lead system designer and implemented initial iterations of a dozen of critical features for a Saas platform built with MeteorJS and ReactJS.
   Responsible for both frontend and backend implementation.
- Collaborated with another team member and completed a sales
  feasibility tool within 2 months without prior knowledge of the
  development framework (ReactJS & Redux). The application saved
  approximately a hundred hours of data-entering each month while
  providing fast user experience and greater accessibility.

#### Software Developer at EcoMotto Inc.

May 2015 - August 2019

- As a full-time employee, designed and built an Android application
  prototype using Java. The application is a part of a larger ecosystem to
  support remote-controlled home thermostats.
- When coming back as a part-time contractor, fully developed a single-page application that remotely controls home thermostats within 1 month.

### **Education**

### Computer Science, The University of Texas at Dallas

August 2011 - May 2015

Recipient of **Academic Distinction Scholarship. Graduated Cum Laude** with 3.6 GPA.

### **Extra-curricular activities**

#### Won 2 Hackathons

 As a student, I participated in several hackathons and won 2 prizes. One was awarded by AT&T for Best Mobile App for Connected Cars.